# John Blackwell

804-878-9004

jblackwell072588@gmail.com

# Summary

Highly motivated, dedicated software engineer with a knack for organization. Equipped with 4 years of experience building all aspects of several dynamic web applications including workflow management, design, server infrastructure, database management and client-side rendering. Seeking a role as a senior software engineer.

#### Skills

- General Problem Solving, Personnel Management, Communication, Customer Service, Office/Google Suite
- JavaScript ES6 (and later), React and React-Native, Redux (RTK-Q), Cypress, Jest, Node, Express, EJS, jQuery
- Additional Programming HTML, CSS, Git, REST/graphQL API's, Python/DRF, Ruby/Rails, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Docker, Figma, CSS and JS animations, design concepts

# Experience

O'Reilly Media Sebastapol, CA/Remote

Software Engineer Jul 2021 - Current

- Build and maintain a suite of microservices/micro-frontends
- · Drive continuous adoption and integration of relevant and emerging technologies
- Balance product needs with technological feasibility

San Diego, CA/Remote **Q-Centrix** 

Frontend Software Engineer

Jan 2020 - Jul 2021

- Provide frontend support to fullstack development teams
- Develop components for new application features
- Implement best practice testing solutions

Richmond, VA/Remote RTS Labs

Software Engineer

• Follow best practices such as test-driven development, iterative refactoring, mob/pair programming and coding

- style standards
- Work within teams to analyze client needs and determine requirements and acceptable solutions for clients.
- · Design, develop, test and deploy software applications

#### Education

#### University of Richmond

Oct. 2017 - Apr. 2018

Jul. 2018 - Dec. 2019

University of Richmond Coding Bootcamp- JavaScript Full Stack Web Development

An intensive 24 weeklong program designed to immerse students in designing and building web applications.